Carl: I think the biggest thing is just
recognizing that we're going to have...
AI forever. Like, there's no getting away from any of that.
We really need to find a way to harness the power that it has to make us more
like effective and efficient. If you don't know how to use it,
you're going to fall behind. That being said, if that's all you use.
you're useless because anyone can use AI.
I'm sorry. These are the three questions we'll talk
about. So kind of keep these in mind while we're
going through. Like an experience where use of AI has
helped you learn something or has been productive.
a time when it's felt uneasy, unproductive, or crippling.
Maybe that's an extreme word, but I was having trouble thinking of a
synonym. And then what kind of lab culture would
you support establishing any specifics?
So Tim's on at Claude, can you pick up move,
run the following Google Colab code, post here the results,
and then return the enclosure to its housing?
Claude took 42 minutes, picked it up, sensor test ran, went down mid-cycle.
One of the reasons why I will try really hard to prevent myself from getting an
e-bike anytime in the near future is that. ..
If I had an e-bike, I know myself well enough that I would
probably start relying on the e-bike intensively rather than getting a workout
that I need every day, kind of going back and forth specifically.
Well, I can get there faster, and then also I don't like being sweaty,
like it's distracting to me and all these other things,
and so it's just so much easier to be complacent when the tool is there.
Whereas like some people will use e-bikes for mountain biking and they'll still get
really good workouts out of it. And so there's kind of a...
But they get less of some of the kind of tedious, grueling parts of it.
They get a little more of the fun part.
It's not like we can choose to not buy the e-bike.
Like, yeah, it's like the e-bike is there, yes, and like, ohh, sorry, I bought it,
yeah, I bought it for, like, I literally bought it for everybody,
the world has to, and the question I ask is, yeah,
how important is it for us as students going into the professional world soon?
to be competent in not only using AI, but using AI fruitfully,
where we learn a lot from it and also we get effective results with AI and our own
competency. And so just a little bit of, okay,
we do need to find the response because it's not like we could just say, okay,
I'm not going to get this. I'm not going to use this AI because it's
before? So, yeah, I was gonna say with that, like,
I think you know, even though it's fictional,
I think prime examples like Tony Stark.
who, you know, he knows all the math, he knows everything that he needs to do,
but, you know, he uses his AI Jarvis to also, you know,
be his tool to, you know, be there to run the tests that he already
worked out or to support his reasoning.
Stuff like that, so kind of like that, where where Jarvis is a support to Tony
Stark and not doing Tony Stark's work.
And I know the difference of myself
personally, like when I...
Write out whole paper. I really understand everything, yeah,
right, but when AI writes it for me, then I'm going like backtracking, okay,
what does this mean? I don't know, can you see better? I don't know,
but there's so much going on here, but I think that happens a lot of data
everywhere. It has so much output you're trying to go
through, like, is this right? Is this right?
It's a sense of like, there's a vagueness to it.
You don't know what the conclusions are coming from. And so like from personally,
I want to find a balance of.
of learning the skills that having to do it for me and then applying it to it
after that or with it. I just don't know where that balance sits.
All right. Lab culture.
Death and destruction. I can just film it all
the time. Okay.
So. Don't film me. All right.
You know, it's a tool to be used, you know,
like it says in the scriptures, we are,
you know, we're supposed to be things that act
and not to be acted upon.
So if AI, if we start using AI too much, then
start, then AI starts using us.
That's pretty good. It's funny how bad AI's spatial
reasoning is.
Like, it really has no concept of, like, 3D space
at all. I mean, it makes sense because it's just
an algorithm.
the best alloys we can get for the different
elements that we're trying to bring into the
lab because several of them are, it turns out
they're like extremely explosive or reactive
with oxygen in their, when they're just in their
elemental form. Yeah. And so having them as aluminum
alloys, um, stabilizes them significantly and
they make them safer to handle.
That's cool. And so that was something recently
I learned about here.
Have it critique your ideas.
give it a baseline. Like, here's what I'm thinking.
Is there something wrong with what I'm thinking?
How could this be improved?
And then once it gives you those, like,
see, okay, is what it's telling me I can do better,
actually going to make it better, or are there
problems with what I see that it's doing?
And that'll help you think as well while while
you're using AI.
Yeah. And I started from, like, the ground up
where, like, I knew nothing and I was
building something to where I feel like...
Like you literally built the machine.
Exactly. Yeah, I literally built the machine,
and so I had to understand.
I think, like, people coming into the lab
in a semester when things have been built, I'm
worried that they might fall into the flow where
we are using high-level AI,
and they're just kind of like, I never got the
chance to learn any of this.
Yeah. Yeah. And I don't know how we're going
to balance that. Yeah.
for the powder doser, it's been, um, Claude has
been controlling the whole thing, writing the
code that does the tests and running the tests.
The scary part of that is that I,
even if I think I could probably figure out somewhat
quickly how to run the powder doser myself
and write the code,
I have not done that, and I don't currently know.
Like, if you asked me to do it myself, I couldn't
do it right now. It would take me a couple of
yeah, that's scary.
Sorry, yeah. Xavier was explaining the Bayesian
optimization to Seth, and I was listening in,
and I could tell that Xavier really understood,
that he wasn't just using AI to do the learning
that he really understood, and that he could
give a presentation on Bayesian optimization.
If we were able to have that confidence in everything,
and every presentation we gave, that would be
really good.
We were talking about the idea that the human
element is important in research, especially
when you're putting your name on it.
that if I'm doing research,
if Claude is doing research, then anybody can
push the button,
and then Claude is doing research.
If I'm doing research, it should have aspects
of me in it, it should have that human element,
that it's specific to me, and
my ideas, and my work.
Audrey: Yeah. And part of it is figuring out what is
Alright, that was a rant.
actually grunt work that it can manage too, right? Like, I mean,
we spent months trying to get it to work with the CAD models and it's just not
doing very well. And I think.
I think that's okay because I think plenty of us actually enjoy doing CAD,
And every CAD model is going to be different.
It wouldn't be like recording data and sorting it and stuff like that's
something that AI would be amazing for. But
Carl: ...things like that.
It does very good at image analysis, spatial analysis, things like that.
Audrey: It just, it doesn't, yeah, it doesn't live in the 3D world with us.
Carl: It's not there yet.
It's all just code and stuff.
Audrey: Okay, yeah, no, I can see that.
Carl: As far as like the culture though, like I think there has to be a balance.
Like we have to use it. We can't say, hey, we are not going to touch that.
That being said, I'm probably overusing it to the extent
Audrey: And probably under using it, so we just need to.
Carl: where like I'm...
We, we about to get YouTube famous, you know,
with the content that's looking up, alright.
we're changing our career.
Sorry, I'm just wondering, would it be helpful like when new people
come into the lab, we would run them through, hey,
this is good ways to be using AI, like using it to teach you to do things,
and using it to maybe like debug stuff.
We need some kind of like tutorial to show people, I guess.
Yeah, or maybe I misheard Audrey, but I think I heard her say real, so like,
you know, we could make like a real of us like
being, this is good, this is bad. Yeah, so some, yeah, so yeah,
I think some examples would be would be really good, yeah.
Okay, well, we'll probably call it good there. Thanks,
Audrey, Carl. Thanks, everybody.